segd.org 2019-05-10

# SEGD PRIVACY AND SECURITY STATEMENT

                                                                                                    1
SEGD PRIVACY AND SECURITY STATEMENT
Last Updated: August 22, 2018
SEGD, the Society for Experiential Graphic Design, values you and recognizes that privacy is
important to you. We want to be transparent about how we collect, use and disclose data.
This Privacy Statement describes our privacy practices for the data we collect:
    •    through our website (the “Website”)
    •    through software applications made available by us for use on or through computers
        and mobile devices (the “Apps”)
    •    through social media pages (our “Social Media Pages”)
    •    through HTML-formatted email messages that we send you that link to this Privacy
        Statement and through your communications with us
    •    when you become a member of SEGD, register and attend one of our events, or
        purchase products or services on-line or through other offline interactions
Collectively, we refer to the Website, the Apps and our Social Media Pages, as the “Online
Services” and, together with offline channels, as the “Services.” By using the Services, you
agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Statement.
Collection of Personal Data
“Personal Data” are data that identify you as an individual or relate to an identifiable individual.
At touchpoints throughout your interactions with SEGD, we collect Personal Data in accordance
with law, such as:
    • Name
    • Job title
    • Employer name and contact details
    • Gender
    • Address
    • Telephone number
    • Email address
    • Credit and debit card number or other payment data (not held in any SEGD property;
        held only by our credit card processor)
    • Financial history with SEGD
    • Generation (e.g., Millennial)
    • Ethnicity (where available)
    • Membership history
    • Profile photo and other data publicly available, or data publicly available on your social
        media
In more limited circumstances, we also may collect:
    • Photographic, video or audio recordings of your likeness if you attended, presented at or
        spoken at an SEGD event, activity or function
    • Spouse’s, children’s and pet’s names and birthdates
We collect available Personal Data to offer a more relevant and personal membership and event
experience and help the profession understand itself better.

                                                                                                     2
If you submit any Personal Data about other people to us or our service providers (e.g., if you
make a registration payment for another individual), you represent that you have the authority to
do so and you permit us to use the data in accordance with this Privacy Statement.
How We Collect Personal Data
We collect Personal Data in a variety of ways:
     • Online Services. We collect Personal Data when you make a purchase or registration
        from our Websites or Apps, communicate with us or otherwise connect with us, post to
        social media pages, sign up for a newsletter or participate in a survey, contest or
        promotional offer.
     • Offline Interactions. We occasionally collect Personal Data when you participate in
        SEGD activities.
     • Contact Staff. We collect Personal Data when you call a member of staff to make an
        offline registration or purchase from SEGD.
     • Volunteer Chapter Chairs. Our volunteer Chapter Chairs collect data occasionally to
        update your contact details or add you to a mailing list for your Chapter.
     • Other Sources. We collect Personal Data from other sources to complete your personal
        profiles; these sources include social media profiles, public databases and websites,
        joint marketing partners and other third parties.
Collection of Other Data
“Other Data” are data that generally do not reveal your specific identity or do not relate directly
to an individual. To the extent Other Data reveal your specific identity or relate to an individual,
we will treat Other Data as Personal Data. Other Data include:
     • Browser and device data
     • Website visit data
     • App usage data
     • Data collected through cookies, pixel tags and other technologies
     • Demographic data and other data
     • Aggregated data
How We Collect Other Data
We collect Other Data in a variety of ways:
     • Your browser or device. We collect certain data through your browser or automatically
        through your device through third party services like Google Analytics. We use this data
        to ensure that the Online Services function properly.
     • Your use of the Apps. When you download and use an App, we collect certain data
        such as App usage data, the date and time the App on your device accesses our servers
        and what data and files have been downloaded to the App based on your device
        number.
     • Cookies. We collect certain data from cookies, which are pieces of data stored directly
        on the computer or mobile device you are using. Cookies allow us to collect data such
        as browser type, time spent on the Online Services, pages visited, referring URL,
        language preferences and other aggregated traffic data. We use the data for security
        purposes, to facilitate navigation, to display data more effectively, to collect statistical
        data, to personalize your experience while using the Online Services and to recognize

                                                                                                  3
        your computer to assist your use of the Online Services. We also gather statistical data
        about use of the Online Services to continually improve design and functionality,
        understand how they are used and assist us with resolving questions. We also use
        cookies to track responses to online advertisements and marketing emails. (If you do not
        want data collected with cookies, you can learn more about controlling cookies here. You
        can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings on your browser. You
        can also manage your tracking preferences by clicking on Tracking Preferences at the
        bottom of our home page.) If you do not accept cookies, you may experience some
        inconvenience in your use of the Online Services. For example, we will not be able to
        recognize your computer and you will need to log in every time you visit. We do not
        respond to browser Do-Not-Track signals.
    •   Pixel Tags and other similar technologies. We may collect data from pixel tags (also
        known as web beacons and clear GIFs) through our third-party service providers, to
        track the actions of users (including email recipients), measure the success of our
        marketing campaigns and compile statistics about usage of the Online Services.
    •   Analytics. We collect data through Google Analytics, which use cookies and
        technologies to collect and analyze data about use of the Services. These services
        collect data regarding the use of other websites, apps and online resources. You can
        learn about Google’s practices here and opt out by downloading the Google Analytics
        opt out browser add-on, available here.
    •   Your IP Address. We collect your IP address, a number that is automatically assigned
        to the computer you are using by your Internet Service Provider (ISP). An IP address is
        identified and logged automatically in our Web Hosting provider’s server log files when a
        user accesses the Online Services, along with the time of the visit and the pages that
        were visited. We use IP addresses to calculate usage levels, diagnose server problems
        and administer the Online Services.
    §   Aggregated Data. We may aggregate data that we collect; this aggregated data will not
        personally identify you.
Use of Personal Data and Other Data
We use Personal Data and Other Data to provide you with Services, to develop new offerings
and to protect SEGD and our customers and members as detailed below. In some instances,
we will request that you provide Personal Data or Other Data to us directly. If you do not provide
the data that we request, or prohibit us from collecting such data, we may not be able to provide
the requested Services.
We use Personal Data and Other Data to personalize our Services and improve your
experience, to manage our contractual relationship with you, for our legitimate business
interests, to comply with a legal obligation and/or because we have a legitimate interest to do
so. In doing so, we:
Provide the Services you request.
    • Facilitate purchases and payments; send administrative information, confirmations or
        event participation messages; and provide you with information about event locations.
    • Process your payment when you purchase a membership, registration or other offering.
    • Support electronic receipts. We use the email address you provide when you make a
        purchase to send you a receipt. If you make a purchase for someone else using your
        email address, we send you that receipt as well; if you do not wish to receive this receipt,

                                                                                                  4
         use the email address of the person you are purchasing for. You can request that the
         email address be changed at any time.
Personalize Services according to your Personal Preferences
     • Communicate with you about goods and services according to your practice areas.
     • Send you targeted marketing communications, promotional offers, and customer
         satisfaction or market research surveys.
     • Focus the placement of your Member Bio on the pages of our Website.
Enable you to benefit from events and promotions and to administer these activities.
     • Provide some Personal Data (name, address, email, phone number, firm name) to
         participants and sponsors of our events
Maintain business commitments.
     • Perform data analysis and audits; develop new goods and services; enhance, improve
         or modify our Services; identify usage trends determine the effectiveness of our
         promotional campaigns; and operate and expand our business activities.
Disclosure of Personal Data and Other Data
     •   Service Providers. We disclose Personal Data and Other Data to third party service
         providers for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement. Examples of service
         providers include companies that provide website development and hosting, data
         analysis, payment processing, order fulfillment, information technology, customer
         service, email delivery, marketing and sponsorship, auditing and other services.
Choices, Access and Retention
You have choices when it comes to how we use your data and we want to ensure you have the
information to make choices that are right for you.
If you no longer want to receive marketing or Services-related emails, you may opt out by
visiting the unsubscribe page at MailChimp (our email service provider) or by following the
instructions in any such email you receive from us.
If you opt out of receiving marketing emails from us, we may still send you administrative
(Services-related) messages from which you cannot opt out.
How You Can Access, Change or Suppress Your Personal Data
If you would like to review, correct, update, suppress, restrict or delete Personal Data that you
have previously provided to us, or if you would like to receive an electronic copy of your
Personal Data for purposes of transmitting it to another company (to the extent this right to data
portability is provided to you by law), you can contact us at segd@segd.org or by mail at:
                 SEGD
                 1900 L Street NW
                 Suite 710
                 Washington, DC 20036
                 USA
In your request, please make clear what Personal Data you would like to have changed,
whether you would like to have your Personal Data suppressed from our database or other
limitations you would like to put on our use of your Personal Data. For your protection, we only

                                                                                                     5
fulfill requests for the Personal Data associated with the particular email address that you use to
send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before fulfilling your request. We
will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable.
Please note that we often need to retain certain data for recordkeeping purposes and/or to
complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting a change or deletion (e.g., when
you make a purchase or reservation, or enter a promotion, you may not be able to change or
delete the Personal Data provided until after the completion of such purchase, reservation or
promotion). There may also be residual data that will remain within our databases and other
records that will not be removed. In addition, there may be certain data that we may not allow
you to review for legal, security or other reasons.
Retention
We will retain your Personal Data for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this
Privacy Statement unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.
The criteria used to determine our retention periods include:
     •     The length of time we have an ongoing relationship or expected relationship with you
          and provide the Services to you.
     •     Whether there is a legal obligation to which we are subject, e.g. certain laws that require
          us to keep records of your transactions for a certain period of time before we can delete
          them.
     •     Whether retention is advisable considering our legal position, such as for statutes of
          limitations, litigation or regulatory investigations
Use of Services by Minors
The Services are not directed to individuals under the age of sixteen (16), and we request that
they not provide Personal Data through the Services.
Cross Border Transfer
SEGD is a global organization with local chapters in many countries. We provide a global
service. Sharing data cross-border is essential to the Services so that you receive the same
high-quality service wherever you are in the world. As a result, we will, subject to law, transfer
Personal Data and Other Data collected in connection with the Services to entities in countries
where data protection standards may differ from those in the country where you reside. By using
our Services, you understand that we transfer your Personal Data globally.
In certain circumstances, courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies or security
authorities in those other countries will be entitled to access your Personal Data.
Some non-EEA countries are recognized by the European Commission as providing an
adequate level of data protection according to EEA standards. The full list of these countries is
available here.
Updates to this Privacy Statement.
The “Last Updated” legend at the top of this document indicates when this Privacy Statement
was last revised. Any changes will become effective when we post the revised Privacy

                                                                                                     6
Statement on the Online Services. Your use of the Services following these changes means that
you accept the revised Privacy Statement. If you would like to review the version of the Privacy
Statement that was effective immediately prior to this revision, please contact us at
segd@segd.org.
Other Uses and Disclosures
We will use and disclose Personal Data as we believe to be necessary or appropriate to:
     • comply with applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence
     • comply with legal process
     • respond to requests from public and government authorities, including authorities
        outside your country of residence, and meet national security or law enforcement
        requirements
     • enforce our terms and conditions
     • protect our operations
     • protect the rights and privacy of SEGD, you or others
     • allow us to pursue available remedies or limit damages we may sustain.
We may use and disclose Other Data for any purpose, except where we are not allowed to
under applicable law. In some instances, we may combine Other Data with Personal Data (such
as combining your name with your location). If we do, we will treat the combined data as
Personal Data as long as it is combined.
Non-SEGD Entities
This Privacy Statement does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, data or
other practices of any entities outside of SEGD, including strategic business partners (e.g.,
sponsors, awards services providers, jobs board providers, listserv providers, payment and
credit card processing services providers) or any third party operating any site or service to
which the Services link. The inclusion of a link on the Online Services does not imply
endorsement of the linked site or service by us. We have no control over, and are not
responsible for, any third party’s collection, use or disclosure of your Personal Data.
In addition, we are not responsible for the data collection, use, disclosure or security policies or
practices of other organizations such as Facebook, Apple, Google, Microsoft, Blackberry or any
other app developer, app provider, social media platform provider, operating system provider,
wireless service provider or device manufacturer, including with respect to any Personal Data
you disclose to other organizations through or the Apps or our Social Media Pages.
Security
We seek to use reasonable organizational, technical and administrative measures to protect
Personal Data. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed as
100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for
example, if you feel that the security of your account has been compromised), please notify us
immediately.
Contacting Us
If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, please contact us at segd@segd.org or
by mail:

                                                                                        7
                SEGD
                1900 L Street NW
                Suite 710
                Washington, DC 20036
                USA
Because your email communications to us may not always be secure, please do not include
credit card or Sensitive Data in your emails to us.
